fetlife.com 2011-08-10

# Privacy Policy - FetLife

Your privacy is very important to us and we want to be transparent about our privacy policies so that you can feel comfortable using and sharing information about yourself on FetLife.

The rule we live by when it comes to making decisions about privacy is:

> “Treat people's information like we would want others to treat ours.”

If you have any questions or feedback on our privacy policy please don't hesitate to email us at [privacy@fetlife.com](mailto:%70%72%69%76%61%63%79@%66%65%74%6c%69%66%65.%63%6f%6d).

### Information You Provide Us

#### Personal Information

To access FetLife you need to sign-up. When you sign-up, you provide us with a nickname people will use to refer to you, your email address, the gender you associate with, your sexual orientation, your role(s) (sexually speaking), date of birth and location. You can also add additional information about yourself once you finished signing-up such as a personal description of yourself, what you are looking for, relationships you are in and fetishes you are into and curious about, amongst other things.

But don't stress about it though, you can visit your profile at any time to modify your personal information. Nothing is permanent.

#### Content

Anything posted on your profile can be removed at any time… it is your profile after all.

You should think twice though before you start or comment on any discussions. To maintain the integrity of discussions we don't remove the original post or any comments unless they break one of our guidelines or our Terms of Use.

#### Transaction Information

If you choose to support FetLife, and we hope you do, you do so through iBill or Zombaio. These are the three 3rd party merchant providers we use to handle all credit card transactions for us. You can view their respective privacy policies [here](http://www.ibill.net/privacy.aspx) and [here](https://secure.zombaio.com/terms_en.asp).

### Information We Collect When You Interact With FetLife

#### Site Activity

We log the actions you take on FetLife such as adding a friend, joining a group, uploading a picture or attending an event. The logs are used to create an activity feed for those who you are friends with.

#### Logs and Analytics

Web servers write to a log file every time you access a page on FetLife. In that log file your IP Address, browser information and page you requested is logged. This is the standard information logged by webservers.

On top of that, we use Google Analytics to better understand how people use FetLife so that we can improve the experience for you. Google Analytics collects the information sent by your browser as part of a web page request. To get a better understanding of how Google uses the information we collect we recommend you read their [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html).

#### Cookies

> "C is for cookie that's good enough for me." - Sesame Street's Cookie Monster.

FetLife uses cookies for authentication and to store information in between page requests. If you want to learn more about cookies you should read the [wikipedia article on HTTP cookies](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie).

At anytime, you can delete the cookies that are on you computer. Instructions: [Safari](http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?path=Safari/3.0/en/11471.html), [Chrome](http://www.google.com/support/chrome/bin/answer.py?answer=95626), Internet Explorer, [Firefox](http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Deleting+cookies?bl=n&s=deleting%20cookies&as=q), and [Opera](http://www.opera.com/support/kb/view/806/).

### How We Use Your Information

#### To Contact You

We use your email address attached to your profile to contact you and send you email notifications. If you want us to contact you using another email address and or not send you certain email notifications please update your settings on FetLife. We do not give sell or share your email address with any third parties. That would be wrong.

#### To Serve Ads

We allow our advertisers to target their ads by location and gender. We use your IP address and gender you specified on FetLife to do the targeting. We use [AdGear](http://adgear.com/)'s ad platform to serve ads for us and we do not give advertisers any information about people who have clicked on their ads. We just give them aggregate non-personally-identifiable information. You can view AdGear's privacy policy [here](http://adgear.com/privacy/).

### How We Share Information

#### Law and Harm

We may disclose your information if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of anyone; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect FetLife's rights or property.

#### Service Providers

We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us. We may share your personal information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services. Our personal information is on FetLife as well, we would never use companies that don't share a similar privacy philosophy as us.

#### Business Transfers

In the event that FetLife is involved in a bankruptcy, merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, your information may be sold or transferred as part of that transaction. The promises in this privacy policy will apply to your information as transferred to the new entity. No, we are not for sale and not planning to sell FetLife. This note is just one of those necessary evils.

### How You Can View and Modify Your Personal Information

Once you login to FetLife you can view and edit your profile and personal information we have on file for you. It's easy cheesy.

### Steps We Take To Protect Your Information

#### We Encrypt Your Password

Believe it or not, a lot of websites still store passwords in plain text so anyone who has access to the database can see your password. We encrypt your password so we have no way to tell what your password is. Fun tip: To see if any specific site encrypts your password request your login information through their login form and if they send you back your password then you know they don't encrypt it.

#### We Use SSL to Login to FetLife

When you login to FetLife it is done over SSL so if someone wanted to try to steal your login credentials when you login they wouldn't be able to sniff it over the network. SSL is the same technology your bank uses when you login to your their website.

#### We Protect You From XSS Vulnerabilities

We have gone to great lengths to protect all members of FetLife from XSS (Cross Site Scripting) vulnerabilities but if you do come across any vulnerabilities please email us ASAP at [security911@fetlife.com](mailto:%73%65%63%75%72%69%74%79%39%31%31@%66%65%74%6c%69%66%65.%63%6f%6d) so we can fix the problem right away.

If you want to learn more about XSS check out [Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) on Wikipedia](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cross-site_scripting).

### General Surgeons Warning

Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot control the actions of other users with whom you share your information. We cannot ensure that information you share on FetLife will not become publicly available. We can't be responsible for third party circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on FetLife. You can reduce these risks by using common sense security practices such as choosing a strong password, using different passwords for different services, and using up to date antivirus software.

### Reporting Violations

You should report any privacy and or security violations to us by emailing us at [privacy@fetlife.com](mailto:%70%72%69%76%61%63%79@%66%65%74%6c%69%66%65.%63%6f%6d)

### Changes to this Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will always be available at <http://fetlife.com/fetlife/privacy>. By continuing to access or use the Services after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

### Got a Question?

Send us an email day or night to [privacy@fetlife.com](mailto:%70%72%69%76%61%63%79@%66%65%74%6c%69%66%65.%63%6f%6d).

last updated  
April 26th, 2010
